Michael Silva

301 Braxman Lane, Holly Springs, NC 27540

(919) 757-4204 | mjsilva918@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/michaelsilva2

Summary

Systems Engineer with more than 12 years of experience, looking to grow within a company and challenge myself with new opportunities. Excellent troubleshooting and diagnostic skills. Proficient documentation skills on daily processes and newly discovered information. Self-starter known to initiate process and system improvements to increase system stability and staff productivity. Ability to learn new skills and technologies quickly and efficiently.

Technical Skills & Tools

- Microsoft Exchange
- Microsoft SharePoint
- VMWare
- Citrix
- FreeNAS
- Windows Server: 2008/2012/2016
- Network Design & Troubleshooting
- Mobile Device Management
- Documentation

- Telephony Solutions
- NTFS File Sharing
- Patch Management
- Backup Solutions & Disaster Recovery
- CloudInfrastructure
- Office 365
- Splunk
- SolarWinds
- Zenoss
- Cisco Prime
 Infrastructure
- Meraki

- Cisco
- Ubiquiti
- SonicWall
- Symantec Backup
 Exec
- Amazon Web Services
- Microsoft Hyper-V
- Veeam
- NetApp Enterprise
 Storage
- Red Hat Enterprise Linux
- Cloud Architecture

Professional Experience

Cisco Systems, Inc. | RTP, NC Platform Engineer

Feb 2018 to Present

 Configure and monitor private cloud UCaaS for government and Department of Defense clients. Windows and Linux server administration, domain services, and device monitoring configuration. Serve as subject matter expert for VMWare for Operations team. Work directly with automation team to continue to automate processes in order expand the ability of the operations team. These implementations provide laaS and management of UCaaS solutions for DoD clients.

 Technical Environment - Solarwinds, VMWare, Splunk, Zenoss, Windows 2012/2016, Active Directory and other domain services, Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.x, Cisco Unified Communication, Cisco UCS servers, NetApp Storage, Cisco security and network devices.

Proton Technologies | Raleigh, NC Lead Engineer

Mar 2015 to Feb 2018

- Serving as Lead Engineer for a managed service partner. Designed, maintained and resolved escalated issues for client infrastructures. Manage alerts derived from network devices and server through SolarWinds dashboard. Sole engineer in charge of maintaining servers, networks and mail for more than 150 clients. Assisted helpdesk of 20 technicians with any tier III issues. Migrated more than 75 clients from on-premise exchange and POP3/IMAP instances to hosted email platforms such as Office 365 and Intermedia. Designed FreeNAS and Buffalo Terastation NAS devices for corporate sharing, backup and replication between sites. Managed all clients ISP and registered domain accounts which included changed DNS and MX records during mail cutovers. Migrated multiple clients from on-premise telephony solution to cloud based 3CX phone systems with a cloud backend hosted on AWS EC2 instances.
 - Technical Environment Windows Server 2008/2012/2016, Active Directory and other domain services, VMWare, Solarwinds, Autotask, Microsoft Exchange, Office 365, Intermedia Hosted Exchange, Google G Suite, 3CX, Datto backup, Cisco Meraki networking to include wireless, switching and routing, Meraki mobile device management, FreeNAS, Spam Hero and McAfee mail filtering.

Computer Service Partners, Inc. | Raleigh, NC Systems Engineer

Jan 2014 to Mar 2015

Serving as the technical lead for multiple managed service customers. Analyzed and implemented solutions for clients based on their needs and budget. Daily monitoring of servers, backup solutions and tier 3 escalated issues. Monitored network devices using N-Able dashboard. Managed clients on-premise exchange and hosted email platforms to include Office 365. Managed all clients ISP and registered domain accounts which included changed DNS and MX records during mail cutovers. Deployed Buffalo Terastation NAS devices for corporate sharing,

backup and replication between sites. Deployed and maintained Citrix desktops, applications and infrastructure.

 Technical Environment - Windows Server 2003/2008/2012, Active Directory and other domain services, VMWare, Solarwinds, N-Able, Autotask, Microsoft Exchange, Office 365, 8x8 and ShoreTel telephony solutions, Datto backup, Cisco networking to include wireless, switching and routing, McAfee mail filtering, Citrix.

American Infrastructure | Worcester, PA Systems Administrator/Tier II Support

Dec 2012 to Jan 2014

- Provided system administration and level II support for more than 1000 users spanning across the Mid-Atlantic region. Designed SharePoint master pages and page layouts, serving as company's SharePoint administrator/developer. Successfully migrated all users from IBM Lotus Notes to Microsoft Exchange 2013 within Microsoft Office 365. Launched and enrolled all tablets and phones for the company into a mobile device management called AirWatch. Monitored remote sites networks with SolarWinds dashboard.
 - Technical Environment Windows Server 2008/2012, Active Directory and other domain services, Microsoft SharePoint 2007/2010, AirWatch mobile device management, Solarwinds, LANdesk ticketing, Microsoft Exchange, Office 365, McAfee mail filtering.

Neovera, Inc. | Reston, VA Systems Administrator/IT Consultant

Sept 2011 to Nov 2012

- Embedded support for financial trading firm, while monitoring and maintaining Windows servers, network devices and desktop workstations. Instituted Dell KACE comprising of a ticketing system, asset management system and knowledge base system. Centralized and condensed systems allowing the company to save money and increase availability for all users. Configured, maintained and monitored backup solution of Symantec Backup Exec 2010. Ensured lifecycle of tape drives from backups were properly followed and maintained. Managed the Avaya telecom system, which consisted of digital, VoIP and polycom phones. Monitored and maintained physical and virtual Windows and UNIX servers using Nagios. Assisted in all compliance audits faced by the client.
 - Technical Environment Windows Server 2003/2008/2012, Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4.x/5.x, Active Directory and other domain services, Avaya hosted telecom solution, Solarwinds, Nagios, Dell KACE ticketing, Microsoft Exchange, McAfee mail filtering, Symantec Backup Exec.

United States Marine Corps | Camp Lejeune, NC Systems Administrator / Data Chief

Nov 2006 to Aug 2011

- Supported systems on different classification platforms including Unclassified, US Secret and NATO Secret. Configured Cisco devices to connect to a satellite based connection while forward deployed to both Iraq and Afghanistan. Was placed in charge of 15 of my peers spanning different military specialties. Served as the Information Assurance Officer for my unit, ensuring that all security policies were being followed and that all unsecure actions were reported. Managed the Cisco VoIP phone system for both Unclassified and US Secret.
 - Technical Environment Windows Server 2003/2008, Active Directory and other domain services, Cisco Unified Communications, Solarwinds, Microsoft Exchange, Cisco networking to include switching and routing, network cabling, network design and maintenance.

Education

DeVry University | Morrisville, NC (Campus & Online)

Computer Information Systems, B.S. | Senior, expected 2019

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Expires 09/2020

Splunk Certified Power User

No expiration

Clearance

Secret Clearance

Dormant, expires 10/2020